A Guide to the Annabelle Cox McCallister Papers, 1930-1983
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Annabelle Cox McAllister Papers, 1930-1983
The Library of Virginia
41199
16.5 cubic feet (37 boxes).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Estate of Annabelle Cox McAllister, Houston, Texas.
Biographical Information
Annabelle Cox was born in Henrietta, Clay County, Texas on 4 February 1904. She was the daughter of David D. Cox (1882-1935) and Nellie Frances Davis (1884-1967). She graduated from William Jewell College in Liberty, Missouri in 1927, and married Edward Nevill McAllister on 29 January 1929. He was born in Paducah, McCracken County, Kentucky on 9 September 1904, and was the son of Edward Severn McCallister (1872-1968) and Pearl Annette Nevill (1876-1971). McAllister also graduated from William Jewell College (1926), and then attended the University of Chicago, graduating in 1928 with a master's degree in chemistry. He was employed by the Esso Oil Company.
McCallister's career in the oil industry took him and his wife to Baton Rouge, Louisiana, then in 1945 to Cranford, New Jersey, and finally to Houston, Texas in 1961. They co-authored two genealogical books, titled Brasfield-Brassfield Genealogies(1959) and Estes Genealogy: Estes Families of Old Clay County, Missouri, Their Ancestors and Their Descendants (1972). Both of the McAllisters were also very active in numerous genealogical and hereditary organizations, and served in officer positions. These groups included the Colonial Dames of America, Daughters of the American Revolution, Houston Genealogical Forum, Huguenot Society of New Jersey, Huguenot Society of Texas, Magna Charta Dames, and the Society of Colonial Wars. Edward Nevill McCallister died in Tulsa, Oklahoma on 13 September 1968. Annabelle Cox McCallister died in Houston, Texas on 13 August 1983. They are both buried in Fairview Cemetery in Liberty, Missouri.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1930-1983, of Annabelle Cox McAllister (1904-1983), and her husband Edward Nevill McAllister (1904-1968), of Houston, Texas, including research for their books Brasfield-Brassfield Genealogies (1959) and Estes Genealogy: Estes Families of Old Clay County, Missouri, Their Ancestors and Their Descendants (1972). There is also information on the allied families of Cox, Davis, Doty, Durrett, Field, Johnson, Kennerly, McAllister, Neville, Newton, Nowlin, Potts, Roberts, Roney, Seamonds, Stone, Townsend, Travis, Wade, Ward, Watts, Willoughby, and Yates. The collection also contains files related to the McAllisters' involvement in various hereditary and patriotic organizations.
The papers include handwritten and typed notes compiled by the McAllisters in their research on the Brasfield and Estes families. They include abstracts, copies, and transcriptions of Bible records, census records, city directories, deeds, land grants, marriage records, military and pension records, tax records, wills, and published sources. There are also genealogical charts and maps. The information was gathered at the New York Public Library, National Archives, Daughters of the American Revolution Library, and on numerous research trips to archives, libraries, and county courthouses in Alabama, Georgia, Kentucky, Louisiana, Maryland, Mississippi, Missouri, North Carolina, South Carolina, Tennessee, Texas, and Virginia. Their research also includes newspapers clippings from the Liberty (Mo.) Chronicle and the Liberty Advance of marriage records and tombstone inscriptions.
There is also a good deal of correspondence from other researchers, as well as other descendants of the Brasfield, Estes, and related families. In addition to the McAllisters' correspondence and research notes, there is information on the publishing and publicity for their two books, reviews and comments, and orders for purchase. There are also typscript drafts of both books, and a master copy of Brasfield-Brassfield Genealogies. Annabelle Cox McAllister had planned to publish a book on the McAllister family, and also a four-volume set of the McAllister's research. The collection includes information on both of these planned works.
The collection also contains material concerning the McAllisters' involvement in various patriotic and hereditary organizations, including the Colonial Dames of America, Daughters of the American Revolution, Houston Genealogical Forum, Huguenot Society of New Jersey, Huguenot Society of Texas, Magna Charta Dames, and Society of Colonial Wars. There are clippings, correspondence, lineage papers, meeting information, membership lists, minutes, newsletters, proceedings, programs, registrar worksheets, reports, and yearbooks. There are files related to the publication of Bible Records 1975: Honoring the Past State Presidents of the Huguenot Society of Texas by that organization.
Other materials in the collection, include biographical information, clippings on the history of Liberty, Clay County, and the State of Missouri, reports by the Virginia Highway and Transportation Research Council on historic roads in Virginia, and materials relating to Annabelle Cox McCallister's selling of silhouettes as an agent for the Kunstverlag Karl Schwalbe in Eisenbach, Germany.
Contents List
- "Abstracts of Wills and Inventories, Fairfax County, Virginia, 1742-1801" by J. Estelle Stewart King. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Addresses/City Directories. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Adjutant General Records. (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
- Alabama, Mississippi, Louisiana, and Texas Research. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Amerman, Cordelia B.. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Antiquarian Booksellers Association. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Baker, Juanita Haydon. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bates, Leisa Miller. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bible Records. (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
- Bible Records Project - Huguenot Society. (Box 1, Folder 12-14)
- Bible Records 1975: Honoring the Past State Presidents of the Huguenot Society of Texas. (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
- Biographical Data. (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
- Book Orders. (Box 2, Folder 7-10)
- Book Orders. (Box 3)
- Book Purchases. (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
- Brassfield. (Box 3, Folder 3-5)
- Brasfield-Brassfield Genealogies - Comments. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Brasfield-Brassfield Genealogies - Master Copy (pp. 1-350). (Box 4)
- Brasfield-Brassfield Genealogies - Master Copy (pp. 351-675). (Box 5)
- Brasfield-Brassfield Genealogies - Master Copy (pp. 676-719). (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Brasfield-Brassfield Genealogies - Printing and Publication. (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
- Brasfield-Brassfield Genealogies - Typescript Draft. (Box 6, Folder 4-11)
- Brasfield-Brassfield Genealogies - Typescript Draft. (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
- Brasfield-Glenn (Sumter County, AL). (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Brassfield - Madison County, KY (James Kimble Young, Jr.). (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Building Forum. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Burlison, Grace Estes. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Card Index of Sources Checked. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- "Cary-Estes Genealogy" by May Polk Webb and Patrick Mann Estes (Portions). (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Cavaliers and Pioneers. (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Census. (Box 7, Folder 10-15)
- Census. (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
- Charts. (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Charts. (Map-case 2, Drawer 13)
- Chestnut Grove Baptist Church (Albemarle County, Va.). (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Clippings. (Box 8, Folder 6-9)
- Clippings - Liberty, Clay County, and Missouri History. (Box 8, Folder 10-12)
- Clippings - Liberty, Clay County, and Missouri History. (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
- Colonial Churches in New Jersey. (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Colonial Dames. (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Cone, Lois Johnson. (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Copyright. (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1969-1980. (Box 9, Folder 7-19)
- Correspondence, 1981-1983. (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
- County Courts Research - Georgia. (Box 10, Folder 4)
- County Courts Research - North Carolina. (Box 10, Folder 5)
- County Courts Research - Virginia. (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Cox. (Box 10, Folder 7-11)
- Cox-Cocks-Cocke. (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Cox-Stone-Berryman-Durrett-Seamonds. (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Crawford, Helen M.. (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Data Collected by Others. (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
- Daughters of the American Colonists. (Box 11, Folder 3-5)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - Baton Rouge Chapter - Library Committee. (Box 11, Folder 6-11)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - Report, 1 April 1940 - 1 April 1941. (Box 12, Folder 1)
- D.A.R. Library - Research Notes. (Box 12, Folder 2)
- D.A.R. Library and Virginia State Library. (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Davis. (Box 12, Folder 4-8)
- Davis Addition - Abstract of Title. (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Davis, Samuel B.. (Box 12, Folder 10-12)
- DeSpain, Daysie Spencer. (Box 12, Folder 13-14)
- Diary - "Trip to the West," 1941. (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Dillingham-Ely (Margaret Wallis Haile). (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Directories. (Box 13, Folder 3-5)
- Doty. (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Doty (Annabel Wilkerson). (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Doty-Brasfield-Davis-Cox. (Box 13, Folder 8-9)
- Durrett. (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Durrett, Eugene Preston. (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Durrett (Maj. O. T. Wills). (Box 13, Folder 12)
- The Edwards and Todd Families by George Hortense Edwards. (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Edwards Brothers, Inc. (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Ely-Dillingham. (Box 13, Folder 15)
- English Records, Virginia Legislative Journals, Virginia Research Notes. (Box 13, Folder 16-17)
- English Research. (Box 14, Folder 1)
- English Research - New York Public Library. (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Ephemera. (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Ernst, Peggy Ruth Estes. (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Errata and Addenda. (Box 14, Folder 5-6)
- Estate of Plum B. Beistle. (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Estes. (Box 14, Folder 8-11)
- Estes Book - Correspondence. (Box 14, Folder 12-14)
- Estes Book - Correspondence. (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
- Estes Book - Sales, Gifts, Reviews. (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
- Estes Chart File. (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Estes Chart File. (Map-case 2, Drawer 13)
- Estes, Elisha (D-6). (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Estes Families of Old Clay County, Missouri: Their Ancestors and Descendants - Typescript Draft. (Box 15, Folder 7-9)
- Estes-Field-Woods. (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Estes - Lunenburg County, VA. (Box 15, Folder 11)
- Estes (Mary Catherine Murphy). (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Estes, Maysel R.. (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Estes - Missouri Miscellaneous. (Box 15, Folder 14)
- Estes, Peter H. (D-61). (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Estes-Townsend-Ward-Field. (Box 16, Folder 2-3)
- Estes, W.G.. (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Estes, William Gilman. (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Evans. (Box 37)
- "Family Name Register," 1958. (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Family Papers (Originals). (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Family Papers (Originals). (Box 37)
- Field. (Box 16, Folder 8-13)
- Field Genealogy by Frederick Clifton Pierce. (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Field-Newton. (Box 16, Folder 15)
- Foster, Helen Colburn - Lineage. (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
- Genealogical Gleanings in England. (Box 17, Folder 3)
- The Genealogical Helper, June 1964 and July 1973. (Box 17, Folder 4)
- The Genealogical Record - Houston Genealogical Forum, 1963, 1973. (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Genealogical Research. (Box 17, Folder 6-7)
- Genealogical Research in Georgia. (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Geographical Index. (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Georgia and South Carolina Research. (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Greeting Cards. (Box 17, Folder 11)
- Harris. (Box 37)
- Harris (Mary D. Robinson). (Box 17, Folder 12-13)
- Herman, Sharon Louise. (Box 17, Folder 14)
- History of Texas Land. (Box 17, Folder 15)
- Hopwood, Mildred Estes. (Box 17, Folder 16)
- Houston Genealogical Forum. (Box 17, Folder 17)
- Howes, Floyd. (Box 17, Folder 18)
- The Huguenot Historian. (Box 17, Folder 19)
- Huguenot Society of New Jersey. (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
- Huguenot Society of Texas. (Box 18, Folder 3-7)
- Huguenot Society of Texas - Return of Property from Miriam Dozier, 1967-1968. (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Huguenot Society of Texas - Yearbooks. (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Hutcheson/Hutchinson. (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Institute of American Genealogy. (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Invitations. (Box 18, Folder 12)
- Ironmonger, Mary. (Box 18, Folder 13)
- "Thomas Jefferson" - Address Before D.A.R. by Landon C. Bell. (Box 18, Folder 14)
- Johnson. (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
- Johnson. (Box 37)
- Johnson, Dr. Lorand V.. (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Johnson (William H.B. Thomas). (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Jones. (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Kavanaugh. (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Keene-Gosnold-Herndon. (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Kennerly. (Box 19, Folder 8-12)
- Kentucky. (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Kentucky Ancestors. (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Kentucky Research. (Box 20, Folder 3-5)
- Kentucky Tax Lists. (Box 20, Folder 6)
- Kindred, Joyce Carver. (Box 20, Folder 7)
- Kosbau, Maxine Lillian Estes. (Box 20, Folder 8)
- "La Grande Tour of 'La Belle Rivere'" by Margaret Strebel Hartman. (Box 20, Folder 9)
- Land Grants. (Box 20, Folder 10)
- Larzalere. (Box 20, Folder 11)
- Libraries - Purchases. (Box 20, Folder 12)
- Longstreth, Evelyn. (Box 20, Folder 13)
- The Louisiana Genealogical Register, June 1974. (Box 20, Folder 14)
- "Magna Charta" by John S. Wurts. (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Magna Charta Barons. (Box 21, Folder 2-3)
- Magna Charta Sureties. (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Main, Mrs. D.C. (Mattie). (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Major. (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Maps. (Box 21, Folder 7)
- Maps. (Map-case 2, Drawer 13)
- Marble Creek Church (Fayette County, KY). (Box 21, Folder 8)
- "John Marr of Stafford County, Va." by M.W. Hiden. (Box 21, Folder 9)
- "Marriage Records of Pioneers of Clay County, Missouri, 1822-1900" - Printed in the Liberty Chronicle and the Liberty Advance. (Box 21, Folder 10-12)
- Maryland Research - Hall of Records. (Box 21, Folder 13)
- Mastin, Grace Murray. (Box 21, Folder 14)
- McAllister. (Box 21, Folder 15)
- McAllister. (Box 22, Folder 1-4)
- McAllister, Annabelle Cox - Lineage. (Box 22, Folder 5-12)
- McAllister Book. (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
- McAllister, Edward Nevill - Letters to Annabelle Cox McAllister, 1966. (Box 23, Folder 3)
- McAllister, Edward Nevill - Lineage. (Box 22, Folder 4-6)
- McCauley. (Box 23, Folder 7)
- McConnell Land - Abstract of Title. (Box 23, Folder 8)
- McCullen, Mary A.. (Box 23, Folder 9)
- McGee-Evans. (Box 23, Folder 10)
- McLain, M.C.. (Box 23, Folder 11)
- McMichen, Elizabeth Estes. (Box 23, Folder 12)
- Memorial Gifts. (Box 23, Folder 13)
- Mercer County, KY 1810 Census. (Box 23, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous. (Box 23, Folder 15)
- Missouri Research. (Box 23, Folder 16-17)
- Missouri Research. (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
- "Morven: A Colonial Outpost of Sensibility" by L. H. Butterfield. (Box 24, Folder 3)
- Murphy, Mary Catherine. (Box 24, Folder 4)
- National Archives - Veterans Records, Land Office Records. (Box 24, Folder 5-6)
- National Genealogical Society Quarterly - Index, 1940, 1959-1972. (Box 24, Folder 7-8)
- National Huguenot Society - Constitution and By-Laws. (Box 24, Folder 9)
- National Society Magna Charta Dames. (Box 24, Folder 10-13)
- National Society Magna Charta Dames. (Box 25, Folder 1-8)
- National Society Magna Charta Dames - Addresses. (Box 25, Folder 9)
- National Society Magna Charta Dames - State Parliaments, 1980-1982. (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
- National Society Magna Charta Dames - State Parliament, 4-6 March 1982. (Box 26, Folder 3)
- National Society Magna Charta Dames - State Parliament Programs. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- National Society Magna Charta Dames - Texas Division. (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Nevill/Neville. (Box 26, Folder 6-7)
- Neville. (Box 26, Folder 8-9)
- Neville-Nevill-Travis. (Box 26, Folder 10)
- Newton. (Box 26, Folder 11)
- Newton - Culpeper County, VA. (Box 26, Folder 12)
- North Carolina Research Notes. (Box 26, Folder 13)
- Obituaries. (Box 27, Folder 1)
- Oil Companies Publications. (Box 37)
- "Oregon Pioneers of 1852 and 1853" by Willetta Moore Smith. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Parks-Early-Metcalfe. (Box 27, Folder 3)
- Pension Records. (Box 37)
- Photographs. (Box 27, Folder 4)
- Potts. (Box 27, Folder 5-8)
- Potts (Hazel M. Henry). (Box 27, Folder 9)
- Potts-Baker (Maxine Davis Baker). (Box 27, Folder 10-11)
- Priest, Whayne C.. (Box 27, Folder 12)
- Property Inventories, Receipts, Insurance. (Box 27, Folder 13)
- Publicity. (Box 27, Folder 14)
- Published Family Records. (Box 28, Folder 1-2)
- Quaker Records in Maryland. (Box 28, Folder 3)
- "Records from Clay County Burial Grounds" - Printed in Liberty Tribune. (Box 28, Folder 4)
- Register of Ancestors - Huguenot Society of New Jersey, 1956. (Box 28, Folder 5)
- Relationships. (Box 28, Folder 6)
- "Research" - Four Volume Set. (Box 28, Folder 7-14)
- Research - Louisiana and Mississippi Court Records. (Box 29, Folder 1)
- Research Notes. (Box 29, Folder 2-4)
- Research Notes - Missouri, 1950. (Box 29, Folder 5-6)
- Research Notes - North Carolina, May 1950. (Box 29, Folder 7)
- Research Notes, May 1951. (Box 29, Folder 8)
- Research Notes - Virginia and Washington, DC, May-June 1951. (Box 29, Folder 9)
- Research Notes - National Archives, November 1951. (Box 29, Folder 10)
- Research Notes - Washington, DC, November 1951. (Box 29, Folder 11)
- Research Notes - Washington, DC, November 1952. (Box 29, Folder 12)
- Research Notes - Washington, DC, 24-31 May 1952. (Box 29, Folder 13)
- Research Notes - Kentucky, Tennessee, Virginia, 30 August - 13 September 1952. (Box 29, Folder 14)
- Research Notes - Kentucky, Tennessee, Virginia, September 1952. (Box 29, Folder 15)
- Research Notes - Washington, DC, 26-27 September 1952. (Box 29, Folder 16)
- Research Notes - Rusk County, TX; Jefferson County, AL; Madison and Culpeper Counties, VA, July-August 1953. (Box 30, Folder 1)
- Research Notes - Washington, DC, 18-23 October 1953. (Box 30, Folder 2)
- Research Notes - D.A.R. Library, August 1954. (Box 30, Folder 3)
- Research Notes - Missouri, 1955. (Box 30, Folder 4)
- Research Notes - Virginia, August and November 1957. (Box 30, Folder 5)
- Research Notes - Census. (Box 30, Folder 6)
- Research Notes - North Carolina. (Box 30, Folder 7)
- Roberts. (Box 30, Folder 8-10)
- Roney. (Box 30, Folder 11-13)
- Roney (Doris Bowers). (Box 30, Folder 14)
- Seamonds (Maude Omohundro). (Box 30, Folder 15-16)
- Seamonds (Elizabeth C. Pierce). (Box 30, Folder 17)
- Seamonds (Bernice Simmons). (Box 30, Folder 18)
- Schumpert, Fleta. (Box 31, Folder 1)
- Silhouettes. (Box 31, Folder 2-4)
- Society of Colonial Wars. (Box 31, Folder 5)
- Some Royal, Noble, and Colonial Ancestors by George Arthur Davis. (Box 31, Folder 6)
- Source Data. (Box 31, Folder 7-9)
- Source Data - Estes and Evans. (Box 31, Folder 10)
- Source Records. (Box 31, Folder 11)
- Sources to Check. (Box 31, Folder 12)
- South Carolina Research. (Box 32, Folder 1)
- Stone, Lucille B.. (Box 32, Folder 2)
- Stone, Mamie E.. (Box 32, Folder 3)
- Stone-Newton-Field-Roberts-Cox. (Box 32, Folder 4-5)
- Stratford Hall. (Box 32, Folder 6)
- Stratton, Mrs. L.L.D.. (Box 32, Folder 7)
- Strode (Berkeley County, VA). (Box 32, Folder 8)
- Strother-Browning-Yates. (Box 32, Folder 9)
- Tennessee Research. (Box 32, Folder 10-11)
- Tourist Brochures. (Box 32, Folder 12)
- Townsend. (Box 32, Folder 13-16)
- Townsend-Nowlin. (Box 33, Folder 1)
- Townsend, Riely Leon. (Box 33, Folder 2-3)
- "Townshend-Townsend Genealogy" by Riely Leon Townsend. (Box 33, Folder 4)
- Travis. (Box 33, Folder 5)
- University Gardens. (Box 33, Folder 6)
- University of Chicago. (Box 33, Folder 7)
- Vacation Diary, 20 August - 6 September 1949. (Box 33, Folder 8)
- Vacation Trips. (Box 33, Folder 9)
- Vaughan, Granville D.. (Box 33, Folder 10)
- Virginia and Kentucky. (Box 33, Folder 11-12)
- Virginia Highway & Transportation Research Council - Albemarle County Roads, 1725-1819. (Box 34, Folder 1)
- Virginia Highway & Transportation Research Council - Albemarle County Road Orders, 1744-178. (Box 34, Folder 2)
- Virginia Highway & Transportation Research Council - Albemarle County Road Orderss, 1783-1816. (Box 34, Folder 3)
- Virginia Highway & Transportation Research Council - Brief History of the Staunton and James River Turnpike. (Box 34, Folder 4)
- Virginia Highway & Transportation Research Council - Early Road Location: Key to Discovering Historic Resources?. (Box 34, Folder 5)
- Virginia Highway & Transportation Research Council - Goochland County Road Orders, 1728-1744. (Box 34, Folder 6)
- Virginia Highway & Transportation Research Council - A Guide to the Preparation of County Road Histories. (Box 34, Folder 7)
- Virginia Highway & Transportation Research Council - Index to Roads in the Albemarle County Surveyors Book, 1744-1853. (Box 34, Folder 8)
- Virginia Highway & Transportation Research Council - Louisa County Road Orders, 1742-1748. (Box 34, Folder 9)
- Virginia Highway & Transportation Research Council - The Route of the Three Notch'd Road: A Preliminary Report. (Box 34, Folder 10)
- Virginia Research. (Box 34, Folder 11-13)
- Virginia Research. (Box 35, Folder 1-3)
- Virginia Research, May 1960. (Box 35, Folder 4)
- Virginia Research Notes. (Box 35, Folder 5-7)
- Wade. (Box 35, Folder 8-9)
- Ward. (Box 35, Folder 10-12)
- Ward-Walker (West Virginia - Marjorie Templeton). (Box 35, Folder 13)
- Watts. (Box 36, Folder 1-3)
- Watts (Mary Harter). (Box 36, Folder 4)
- Watts (Texie Preston. (Box 36, Folder 5-6)
- West Virginia Department of Archives and History - Biennial Report, 1938. (Box 36, Folder 7)
- West Virginia History, July 1941. (Box 36, Folder 8)
- "West Virginians in the Revolution". (Box 36, Folder 9)
- William Jewell College Class of 1926 Alumni Day. (Box 36, Folder 10)
- Willoughby. (Box 36, Folder 11-12)
- Woods-Potts-Cox. (Box 36, Folder 13)
- Woodson-Fleming. (Box 36, Folder 14)
- Writing Guide. (Box 36, Folder 15)
- Wulfeck, Dorothy Ford. (Box 36, Folder 16)
- Yates. (Box 36, Folder 17-22)
- Yates-Shirley-Gaines-Wyman-Browning-Courtney (Basic Data on Yates Line from Mrs. N.D.B. Kinnison). (Box 36, Folder 23)
- Your Family Tree by David Starr Jordan and Sarah Louise Kimball. (Box 36, Folder 24)